molinahealthcare.com 2014-05-18

# terms_privacy

**PLEASE READ THESE TERMS OF USE AND PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY.**

By using this site, you agree to these Terms and Conditions of Use, as well as the Privacy Policy contained therein (collectively referred to as the "Terms of Use"). Your access to this site is subject to the Terms of Use we establish as well as all applicable laws.

### WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY

### COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Molina Healthcare respects the privacy of its customers and other visitors to its website. We want you to know how we handle the information we receive from you via the Internet.

**Public Websites**

When you visit our public websites, no personal information-such as your name, date of birth or telephone number -is collected, unless you provide us with that information voluntarily. Molina Healthcare will not sell, license, transmit or disclose this information outside of Molina Healthcare and its affiliated companies unless (a) expressly authorized by you, (b) necessary to enable Molina Healthcare's contractors or agents to perform certain functions for us, or (c) required or permitted by law. In all cases, we will disclose the information consistent with applicable laws and regulations and we will require the recipient to protect the information and use it only for the purpose it was provided.

If you chose to submit personal information through the Website about yourself or a family member by using the online contact form or our email address, that information may be utilized to assist you with your inquiry. There are some locations on our site where we have made special provisions for a more secure environment in which we can exchange information with you. When you submit your personal information through our secure Web forms, it is protected by encryption.

You should also be aware that when you visit our websites, we collect certain information that does not identify you personally, but may identify your internet protocol (IP) address, or may provide us with "usage data" such as the number of visitors we receive or the pages that are visited most often. This data helps us deliver targeted information to you, and better analyze and improve the usefulness of the information we provide on our websites.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

Like most commercial website owners, we may also use what is known as "cookie" technology. A "cookie" is an element of data that a website can send to your browser when you link to that website. It is not a computer program and has no ability to read data residing on your computer or instruct it to perform any step or function. By assigning a unique data element to each visitor, the website is able to recognize repeat users, track usage patterns and better serve you when you return to that site. The cookie does not extract other personal information about you, such as your name or address. Most browsers provide a simple procedure that will enable you to control whether you want to receive cookies by notifying you when a website is about to deposit a cookie file.

On some pages of the Molina Healthcare website we may also use action tags, sometimes referred to as web beacons or 1x1 pixel graphics interchange format (“GIF”) images. We use these tags to monitor and assess the effectiveness of promotions and marketing. These tags work in combination with cookies, but do not collect or contain any personal information.

**Secure Website Services**

Certain online services are available to Molina Healthcare members via our Secure Website Services. The Secure Website Services require a password to log in before accessing information. Molina Healthcare complies with the requirements under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA). Molina Healthcare may use and share the information that you provide to us via our Secure Website Services to provide you with your healthcare benefits. Users of Molina Healthcare's Secure Website Services should read Molina Healthcare's applicable Notice of Privacy Practices, which explains in more detail how we use and disclose your protected health information. Click on your state to view the HIPAA Notice of Privacy Practices: California | Florida | Illinois | Michigan | New Mexico | Ohio | South Carolina | Texas | Utah | Washington | Wisconsin.

Users of Molina Healthcare's Secure Website Services understand that the confidentiality of individually identifiable health information is protected by federal and state law. By using Molina Healthcare's Secure Website Services you represent to Molina Healthcare that you are either (i) the individual to whom this account pertains, or (ii) legally authorized under applicable law to receive health care information regarding, and to make healthcare decisions for, the individual to whom this account pertains (for example, as the parent, legal guardian or legal custodian of such individual).

**Your E-Mail**

We want to hear your comments and questions and have provided several phone numbers, mailing addresses, and e-mail addresses throughout this Website for that purpose. However, you should be aware that most e-mail systems currently are not protected from third parties, who may be able to access your e-mail without your knowledge or permission. In order to protect your privacy, please do not use e-mail to communicate information to us that you consider confidential. If you wish to communicate such information please use one of our secure Web forms, or phone numbers/mailing addresses provided.

**ONLINE SECURITY**

Molina Healthcare uses reasonable and appropriate security measures to safeguard the information that we have collected from you at our Website. Among the measures that Molina Healthcare has implemented for this Website are administrative, physical and technical safeguards.

**DISCLAIMER**

Molina Healthcare continually updates the information provided on its websites in order to keep the information as current and accurate as possible, however, it is possible that the websites may contain inaccuracies, errors or unauthorized modifications by third parties. Molina Healthcare does not make any express or implied warranties as to the accuracy of any information on its websites. Information contained in our websites may be changed or updated without notice.

Any links to other non-Molina Healthcare websites are solely for your convenience in obtaining related information. Such inclusion or mention does not constitute or imply a recommendation or endorsement by Molina Healthcare. Molina Healthcare does not control the contents of these websites and does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any such information.

The information presented on our websites is not intended to constitute an offer to sell or a solicitation in connection with any service. If you are interested in any of Molina Healthcare's services, please contact us for a complete description of the product and its availability.

**OWNERSHIP, LICENSE AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE OF MATERIALS**

This website is owned and operated by Molina Healthcare, all material contained in our websites is protected by law. All copyright, service mark and other proprietary notices must be kept intact.

**LIMITATIONS OF LIABILITY**

Under no circumstances including, but not limited to, negligence, shall Molina Healthcare or any of its related, affiliated companies be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, special, consequential or punitive damages that result from the use of, or the inability to use the Molina Healthcare material. You specifically acknowledge and agree that Molina Healthcare is not liable for any defamatory, offensive or illegal conduct of any user. If you are dissatisfied with any of the Molina Healthcare material, or with any of Molina Healthcare's terms of use and conditions, your sole and exclusive remedy is to discontinue using this Website.

**NOT A SUBSTITUTE FOR PROFESSIONAL HEALTH CARE OR ADVICE**

The information contained in this site is general in nature and is intended for educational purposes only. It is not a substitute for the advice of health care professionals. If you have specific health care needs, or for complete health information, please see a doctor or other health care provider.

**JURISDICTION**

Except as described otherwise, all materials in the Molina Healthcare sites are made available only to provide information about Molina Healthcare. Molina Healthcare controls and operates this site from its headquarters in Long Beach, California, USA, and makes no representation that these materials are appropriate or available for use in other locations. If you use this site from other locations you are responsible for compliance with applicable local laws.

Updated: February 28, 2014

return to the top
